seven things i wish i remembered before
starting oak chem number one
drawing lewis structures it's already
giving you the order in which uh like
how to actually start drawing the
structure so i'm going to start off with
ch3 knowing that carbon is here it's
surrounded by
three hydrogens
next this carbon is bonded to the next
carbon that follows
and then this carbon is bonded to
hydrogen and to oxygen so i'm going to
place oxygen here and hydrogen here
all right this is not telling us that
they're bonded to each other if that
were the case it would have said oh
now in this case carbon is not happy it
doesn't follow the octet rule right now
it wants to it always needs to follow
that octet rule when we're drawing these
structures so what we need to do is see
this would be incorrect instead one pair
of lone pairs would actually
form a double bond
and this would be the correct structure